Where do you go when you've gone too far?
Unfaithful is a thriller, drama, romance film directed by Adrian Lyne.
Connie is a wife and mother whose 11-year marriage
to Edward has lost its sexual spark.
When Connie literally runs into handsome book collector Paul,
he sweeps her into an all-consuming affair.
But Edward soon becomes suspicious and decides to confront the other man.
Edward Sumner, played by Richard Gere.
Constance Sumner, played by Diane Lane.
Paul Martel, played by Olivier Martinez.
Charlie Sumner, played by Erik Per Sullivan.
Detective Dean, played by Zeljko Ivanek.
Detective Mirojnick, played by Gary Basaraba.
Unfaithful is a 2002 American erotic thriller film produced and directed by Adrian Lyne and written by Alvin
Sargent and William Broyles Jr., adapted from the Claude Chabrol film The Unfaithful Wife (1969).
Starring Richard Gere, Diane Lane, Olivier Martinez, and Erik Per Sullivan, the film follows a couple (Lane and Gere) living in the suburbs of New
York City whose marriage is jeopardized when the wife embarks on an affair with a stranger (Martinez) she encounters by chance.
Unfaithful was theatrically released in the United States on May 10, 2002, and was
screened at the 37th Karlovy Vary International Film Festival on July 8, 2002.
The film was a box office success, grossing $119.1 million
against its $50 million production budget.
Despite mixed reviews from critics, Lane received
critical acclaim for her performance.
Lane won the Satellite Award for Best Actress – Motion Picture Drama at the 7th Satellite Awards, and was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actress at the 75th Academy Awards, the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama at the
60th Golden Globe Awards, the Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Female Actor in a Leading Role at the 9th Screen Actors Guild Awards, and the Critics' Choice Movie Award for Best Actress at the 8th Critics' Choice Awards.
The film was Adrian Lyne’s final directorial effort
for 20 years until Deep Water (2022).
The film explores themes of adultery, infidelity,
new york city, literature, eroticism.
The tone is emotional and intense.